AEKTA KAPASI

603.233.3365 avkapasi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/aektakapasi aektakapasi.github.io

PROFILE

A versatile problem solver with 9 years of experience leading and delivering mission critical business, design, and technology solutions that help Fortune 500 companies, non-profit institutions, and entrepreneurial ventures create value for their stakeholders. Mitigates risks in fast paced, cross-functional environments by building trust with stakeholders, critically assessing organizational needs, and systematically translating requirements into sustainable, highly adopted technology solutions.

COMPETENCIES

Product Design, User Experience, Mobile Design, Front-End Design and Development, Content Management, Business Intelligence, Visual Design, Cognitive Psychology, Agile, Lean, PaaS, SaaS

EXPERIENCE

TANGLED WEB COMMUNICATIONS

2010-PRESENT

Vice President of Experience

Defined and implemented lean user centered design standards, processes, and tools that decreased the time to market and increased the adoption and usability of iOS and Android mobile apps.

Architected and built a modular design system for Tangled's app development platform that reduced the time to design and build user interfaces by 80% over 3 years and ensured a consistent user experience across channels, platforms, and devices.

Architected the mobile app experience and designed the brand identity for 4 early stage ventures including Decnut, a University of Pennsylvania medical venture which won \$50K from Ben Franklin Ventures.

AK DESIGN 2013-PRESENT

Designed brand identities and built responsive websites for new ventures, including 2 Stanford University affiliated biotechnology ventures.

SLALOM CONSULTING 2010-2013

Defined scope, managed requirements, and delivered over \$3,500,000 worth of user accepted business and technology mobile, content management, and customer relationship management solutions for clients including Amgen, Mattel, and Warner Bros. Interactive Entertainment.

Mobile Center of Excellence Lead at Amgen

Defined, planned, and delivered 3 of Amgen's global mobile center of excellence initiatives that evaluated and recommended how to streamline cross-functional collaboration for 18,000 employees around the world.

Mobile Lead at Mattel

Managed Mattel's global mobile device management assessment that resulted in technology executives implementing a solution to ensure employees securely accessed corporate data.

HITACHI CONSULTING 2007-2010

Business Intelligence Analyst at Yale University

Managed requirements and executive adoption for Yale's capital planning solution that allowed executives to quickly and confidently allocate over \$500 million to strategic projects, thereby increasing cash flow predictability for rolling 10 year periods.

Business Intelligence Analyst at Freddie Mac

Defined and implemented enterprise reporting data quality strategies for Freddie Mac that increased financial accountability and transparency. Co-managed data and report requirements, defects, and deployments.

U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES

3/2003-5/2003

AEKTA KAPASI

603.233.3365 avkapasi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/aektakapasi aektakapasi.github.io

EDUCATION

BABSON COLLEGE 2003-2007

Bachelor of Science in Business Management, Entrepreneurship, Magna Cum Laude

LONDON SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS AND POLITICAL SCIENCE

2005-2006

General Course, International Relations and International Development

PHILLIPS EXETER ACADEMY 1999-2003

PROFICIENCY

METHODOLOGY

Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Agile Scrum, Lean Startup, Lean UX, User Centered Design

TECHNOLOGY

LANGUAGES

HTML, XHTML, CSS, JQuery, SQL

MOBILE PLATFORMS

iOS, Android, Windows

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

PhoneGap, Xcode

MOBILE DEVICE AND CONTENT MANAGEMENT

AirWatch, MobileIron

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE

Hyperion (Planning, Essbase, Excel Add-In)

CONTENT MANAGEMENT

Microsoft SharePoint, WordPress

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

IBM Rational (Doors, ClearCase, ClearQuest), VersionOne, Trello, Github

DESIGN

Adobe (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Acrobat, Livecycle), Axure, Balsamig, Final Cut Pro

GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEMS

QGIS

LANGUAGE

German (limited working proficiency), Japanese (conversational)